cefcu.com 2019-11-11

# Privacy Policy - CEFCU

### Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Citizens Equity First Credit Union ("CEFCU") and its wholly-owned subsidiary, CEFCU Financial Services®, Inc., are committed to keeping personal financial information about you, your accounts, and your transactions confidential as required by federal and state laws. This joint notice explains our privacy policies and practices regarding the information we collect from or about you, how we protect that information, the sharing of that information to better serve your financial needs, and your choices about our sharing that information. This joint notice applies to members (including non-member joint account owners), former members, and customers.

### Our Affiliated Companies

  * Citizens Equity First Credit Union
  * CEFCU Financial Services, Inc.

### Collecting Your Information

What information is collected by us? Information that we collect about you may come from any or all of the following sources, and is considered "collected information":

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms — such as your name, address, Social Security number, assets, income, and beneficiaries;
  * Information about your transactions with us or with others, such as your account balance, payment history, parties to transactions, credit card usage, policy coverage, or premiums paid;
  * Information we receive from communications and interactions that we have with you, such as financial or insurance needs you have told us about or concerns you have expressed; and,
  * Information we receive from consumer reporting agencies, such as your creditworthiness and credit history.

### Protecting Your Information

How do we safeguard information about you? We maintain security procedures to protect your non-public personal information. In so doing, we employ physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable state and federal laws, regulations and guidelines to guard your nonpublic personal information.

We restrict access to nonpublic personal information about you to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you.

We require companies that perform services for us or functions on our behalf to agree not to disclose or use your non-public personal information except to perform the services for us. We select these companies very carefully and only work with those who agree to maintain strict confidentiality protections and limit the use and redisclosure of the information we provide. These companies receive only the information needed to perform the marketing or other services on our behalf, and they are not permitted to use it in any other way, including selling or redisclosing the information to any other third party.

### Information Sharing

Is information about me shared within your Affiliated Companies or with non-affiliated companies? From time to time, there may be products and services, either from our Affiliated Companies or from businesses that are not affiliated with us, which we think may be of interest to you. To offer such products and services to you, we may need to share your information with our Affiliated Companies or with non-affiliated companies.

### Former Members or Customers

If your relationship with us ends, your collected information may be shared in the same way, and with the same parties, as is the information about our existing members or customers, all as described in this notice.

### Sharing with Our Affiliated Companies

Is information about me shared within your Affiliated Companies? In our efforts to better serve your financial needs, we may share your collected information described above within our Affiliated Companies. This means CEFCU shares your collected information with CEFCU Financial Services, Inc. and CEFCU Financial Services, Inc. shares your collected information with CEFCU. We want to be sure we understand your entire relationship with us when addressing your needs, providing you services, developing products, and determining what products you may want to know about.

There are some types of collected information that you may ask us not to share with our Affiliated Companies, including:

  * Information we obtain from your application — such as your income, assets, and employer;
  * Information we obtain from a consumer report, such as your credit score or credit history with others;
  * Information we obtain to verify representations made to us by you — such as your creditors, outstanding loans, or open lines of credit with others; and,
  * Information we obtain from another person regarding your employment, credit or other relationships, such as your employment history.

You have a choice as to whether or not you want this information shared with our Affiliated Companies. If you prefer that we not share this information with them, you may opt out.

### Opting Out with Our Affiliates

If you prefer that we not share the types of information described above with our Affiliated Companies, you may opt out, that is, you may direct us not to share the information, by printing, completing, and mailing the Mail-in Form (PDF, 74 KB). If you are a resident of California, you will also need to complete the Important Privacy Choices for Consumers Form (PDF, 44 KB). By opting out you will also opt out from receiving some but not all marketing offers from an Affiliated Company with whom you have no direct relationship. (See "Affiliate Marketing Opt Out".) We are permitted by law to share with our Affiliated Companies information about your transactions and experiences with us (such as your account balances and transaction history), even if you have opted out.

### Sharing with Non-Affiliates

Is information about me shared with non-affiliated entities? We may disclose information we receive from you, limited to your name and address and information about your transactions with us — such as your account balance, payment history, parties to transactions, credit card usage, policy coverage, or premiums paid ("transaction information") to non-affiliated third parties as permitted by law, such as:

  * Third parties that provide services necessary to effect, administer, or enforce a transaction that you request or authorize;
  * Credit bureaus or similar reporting agencies to whom we may report information about your account. Late payments, missed payments, or other defaults on your account may be reflected in your credit report; and,
  * Law enforcement officers and governmental agencies and courts as may be permitted by a subpoena, court order, or law.

We may also disclose your transaction information to non-affiliated third parties that perform marketing or other services for us or functions on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements.

We may disclose your transaction information to the types of nonaffiliated third parties described above, even if you have opted out.

In order to provide products or services which we think may be of interest to you, we may also disclose your transaction information to:

  * Non-affiliated financial service providers — such as securities broker-dealers and insurance companies or agents; and
  * Non-affiliated, non-financial companies — such as trust companies, retailers, direct marketers, airlines, and publishers.

You have a choice as to whether or not you want your transaction information disclosed to the two categories of non-affiliated entities described directly above. If you prefer that we not share that information with them, you may opt out. Your opt out direction will apply to all products and services you obtain from us.

### Opting Out with Non-Affiliates

If you prefer that we not share your transaction information with the non-affiliated financial service providers or with non-affiliated, non-financial companies, as described above, you may opt out, that is, you may direct us not to share the information (other than disclosures permitted by law), by printing, completing, and mailing the Mail-in Form (PDF, 74 KB). If you are a resident of California, you will also need to complete the Important Privacy Choices for Consumers Form (PDF, 44 KB).

### Affiliate Marketing Opt Out

We are giving you this notice to tell you about your choice to limit marketing from our Affiliated Companies by opting out. Under federal law you have the right to limit some but not all marketing from our Affiliated Companies.

You may limit an Affiliated Company, such as CEFCU Financial Services, Inc., from marketing their products or services to you based on your personal information that it received from CEFCU. This information may include your income, your account history with us, and your credit score.

In our efforts to better serve your financial needs, any Affiliated Company with whom you have an existing business relationship may continue to send marketing offers directly to you. Your choice is to limit marketing offers from an Affiliated Company with whom you do not have a direct relationship. If you prefer that an Affiliated Company with whom you do not have a direct relationship not use your personal information that it received from the other Affiliated Company to market to you, you may opt out, that is, you may direct us not to allow that Affiliated Company to use such information to market to you (other than as permitted by law), by printing, completing, and mailing the Mail-in Form (PDF, 74 KB). Your choice to limit marketing offers from our Affiliated Companies will apply until you tell us to change your choice. If you are a resident of California, you will also need to complete the Important Privacy Choices for Consumers Form (PDF, 44 KB).

### Joint Accounts

If you have joint ownership of an account, either owner may opt out for himself/herself and for any of the other owners of the account by printing, completing, and mailing the Mail-in Form (PDF, 74 KB). If you are a resident of California, you will also need to complete the Important Privacy Choices for Consumers Form (PDF, 44 KB). This joint opt out will apply to all accounts and relationships each joint owner has with us. (For example, if you have a joint account with John, and you opt out for yourself and John, we will not share any information from any other account either of you has with us, unless otherwise permitted by law.)

### Multiple Relationships

If you have more than one relationship with our Affiliated Companies, you only have to opt out once.

### Duration of Opt Out

Your opt out choices remain effective until you revoke them in writing. If your relationship with both of our Affiliated  
Companies terminates, your opt out choices will continue to apply. However, if you subsequently re-establish your relationship with us, your opt out choices will not apply to your new relationship. If you wish to opt out, you will need to do so again.

### Changes

Should you change your opt out choices, you may do so by writing us a letter and mailing it to:

Citizens Equity First Credit Union  
Compliance Department  
5401 W. Dirksen Parkway  
P.O. Box 1715  
Peoria, IL 61607

We reserve the right to change this notice in the future, and we will notify you as required by law.

If you have any questions about CEFCU's Privacy Policy, email CEFCU.

### Website Privacy Policy

## Website Privacy Policy

CEFCU is committed to protecting the privacy of members and other visitors to the CEFCU website. To that end, CEFCU has adopted the following website Privacy Policy:

### Website Pages

CEFCU's Internet Service Provider (ISP) collects and stores information on the domain you use to access the CEFCU website, the Internet site from which you linked directly to it, the browser you are using, and the date and time of your visit. This information is used to measure the number of visitors to various pages on the CEFCU website and to help CEFCU make improvements to the information contained therein.

### Email

Personal information contained in email sent to CEFCU by members and non-members may be used by the Credit Union's Staff to answer questions, to follow up on suggestions or complaints, or to improve the level of service CEFCU provides. CEFCU does not transfer information sent via email to third parties, nor does CEFCU permit third parties to make use of information sent to CEFCU via email. Please be advised that email may not be secure against interception by unauthorized individuals.

### Ad Submission Form, CEFCU On-Line® Sign-Up Request Form, Representative Contact Form, and Similar Forms

Information submitted through any of these forms may be used by the Credit Union's Staff to perform a specific function or fulfill a member request as noted on the individual form. CEFCU does not transfer this information to third parties, nor does CEFCU permit third parties to make use of this information.

### Cookies

In order to provide certain Web-based services and to make your online experience more personalized, we may use cookies as part of our interaction with your Internet browser. A cookie is a very small piece of information stored on your local computer so it can later be read by our Web server. CEFCU uses cookies to display information more effectively to you and to gather data about usage of our website. Cookies allow us to collect technical and navigational information — such as browser type, time spent on our site, and pages visited or track activity relating to our online promotions. This information is anonymous and does not include personal information. We retain, aggregate, monitor, and analyze the use of our site so we can continually improve the design, usability, and functionality to better serve you.

You can disable and delete cookies by accessing your browser's preferences menu; however, you should be aware that when cookies are disabled, other online account services provided through CEFCU, like CEFCU Online Home Banking or Bill Payment, may not work properly. For more information on working with cookies, consult the Help function of your browser.

### Weblinking

CEFCU is committed to providing you with the most complete information possible to help you make sound financial decisions. As a convenience to you, CEFCU may link from this website to other websites or Internet resources operated by third parties. When you link from the CEFCU site to a third-party site, the linked site will appear in a new browser window or an alert will appear to notify you that you are leaving the CEFCU site.

Links to third-party sites are solely for informational purposes and should not be construed to endorse or guarantee information or services provided on the linked site except as noted. CEFCU does not control third-party sites and is not responsible for the content on linked sites. CEFCU's Privacy Policy may also differ from third-party site privacy, security, and other policies. Please review a linked site's policies before providing personal information. In the event you conduct a transaction on a linked site, CEFCU will not represent either members or the owner of the linked or accessed site.

CEFCU is committed to providing you with quality online service. If you find any information on the CEFCU website that you believe to be inaccurate or have concerns about a link to a third-party site, please email CEFCU.
